# **Ivan Symchych**

Software Engineer from Lviv, Ukraine

**Email:** ivan.symchych@gmail.com

Github: isymchych

LinkedIn: ivansymchych

### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack software developer with 11 years of experience, seeking for interesting projects. Systems thinker, pragmatic, result-oriented. I enjoy finding simple solutions to complicated problems. Know about clean code, teamwork, documentation and tests. Committed to professional growth.

# **TECHNICAL HIGHLIGHTS**

- TypeScript, JavaScript, Rust, Java, SQL, GraphQL
- HTML, CSS, SCSS, CSS-in-JS
- 00P/00D, FP, Design Patterns, SOLID, REST
- · Linux, Emacs

I'm expert in TypeScript and JavaScript, love and enjoy Rust, and, earlier in my career, used to code in Java. Last few years I was working primarily with Node.js, React/Redux, GraphQL, REST, HTML, SCSS, CSS-in-JS, and a bit of Angular.

Also I have experience with HTML5 video streaming and WebRTC.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Consultant at Remit**

April 2016 – February 2021

# Web Frontend for MaginePro, video streaming company

MaginePro is a white label OTT platform. I helped to build the single page application in React and prerendering server in Node.js. Application is highly customizable via feature flags and scales for multiple partners, which could be configured on the fly.

Also I was working on a cross-platform video player, Chromecast receiver application, introduced end-to-end tests and automated internal processes.

React, Redux, Fela, Typescript, Node.js, GraphQL

#### Calendar application for ThinkTank, the platform for collective intelligence

Single page calendar application for managing events and appointments using REST API in Java. I took part in both front end and back end development.

Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, SASS, Java, Spring

# Consultant at SoftServe

August 2015 - April 2016

## Jitsi Meet for Atlassian

I was refactoring and fixing bugs in Jitsi.org web app, open-source video conferencing solution.

ES6, Babel, Lodash, JQuery

# HipChat for Atlassian

I was working on React-based web UI for HipChat, team chat from Atlassian. I took part in refactoring, bugfixing and writing unit and integration tests.

ES6, React, Lodash, Karma, Selenium

# Java/JavaScript developer at Intellias

July 2012 - August 2015

# Secure online chat peer.me for Tenios, German VoIP service provider

Web chat which leverages the power of WebRTC, cutting-edge technology which allows browsers to communicate with each other without a server (peer-to-peer), with end-to-end encryption. I was working on JS library which enacapsulates core functionality like sending encrypted text messages and files, synchronizing data between clients, establishing group audio and video calls. Also I took part in development of SPA UI and back end.

Java, WebSockets, WebRTC, Marionette.js, Tomcat, Jasmine

# Web portal and utilities for Tenios, German VoIP service provider

Web portal is an SPA for customers to manage their phone numbers, routing plans, bills, calls forwarding etc., and admin portal to manage customers and internal business processes. Backend was implemented as a REST API. I took part in both front end and back end development.

Java, Spring, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Marionette.js, Bootstrap

### Web portal for RPLab, diagnostic laboratory from Belgium

Web frontend for ETL process on client medical data. As a result, system also generates per-client reports in html or pdf formats. I took part in both front end and back end development.

Java, Spring, MongoDB, JSP, Stripes, FlyingSaucer, JFreeChart

# Java Developer at JSC Kredobank

July 2010 - July 2012

### Web services to aggregate and simplify internal business processes

I was working on design, development, bugfixing and support of internal web services. Also I built a GUI client in Swing for those web services.

Java, JBoss, SOAP, WSDL, Oracle 11g, Jenkins CI, Gradle

# **EDUCATION**

Master's degree in Applied Mathematics, Ivan Franko National University Of Lviv, Ukraine, 2007 - 2013

## **LANGUAGES**

- Ukrainian Native
- English Proficient
- Russian Limited working proficiency

# **INTERESTS**

programming, science fiction & popular science, traveling, hiking, computer games